{
  "questions":[
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "When force and displacement are along in the same direction, then work is...",
      "correct_answer": "A) Positive",
      "options": [
          "A) Positive",
          "B) Negative",
          "C) Zero",
          "D) None of These"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A body is displaced by 2m in the y-direction by a force (-4, 2, 6) N. Then work is...",
      "correct_answer": "B) 4J",
      "options": [
          "A) 2J",
          "B) 4J",
          "C) 1J",
          "D) 4.5J"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The power of a pump, which can pump 200kg of water to a height of 200m in 10sec is...",
      "correct_answer": "C) 400KW",
      "options": [
          "A) 40KW",
          "B) 80KW",
          "C) 400KW",
          "D) 960KW"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Two bodies of masses 1kg & 2kg have equal momentum than the ratio of their K.E...",
      "correct_answer": "A) 2:1",
      "options": [
          "A) 2:1",
          "B) 3:1",
          "C) 1:3",
          "D) 1:1"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A bomb of mass 30kg at rest explodes into two pieces of masses 18kg & 12kg. The velocity of the 18kg mass is 6m/s. K.E of the other mass.",
      "correct_answer": "D) 240J",
      "options": [
          "A) 486J",
          "B) 490J",
          "C) 1020J",
          "D) 240J"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A particle of mass m is moving in a circle of constant radius 'r' such that radial acceleration a = kt^2. Then the relation between power (p) and time (t) is...",
      "correct_answer": "B) mkr^2t^2",
      "options": [
          "A) kt^3m^3r^2",
          "B) mkr^2t^2",
          "C) m^2krt^2",
          "D) mktr"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A body of mass (m) is in vertical motion under the influence of gravity then...",
      "correct_answer": "B) K.E decrease & work (-ve) during downward motion",
      "options": [
          "A) Work will be (-ve) & K.E increase during upward motion",
          "B) K.E decrease & work (-ve) during downward motion",
          "C) K.E increase when the body is projected up work (+ve)",
          "D) Work will be (+ve) & K.E decrease during fall"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following is not a conservative force?",
      "correct_answer": "C) Frictional force",
      "options": [
          "A) Gravitational force",
          "B) Restoring force",
          "C) Frictional force",
          "D) All of These"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A particle of mass 10gm is kept on the surface of a Uniform sphere of mass 100kg and radius 10cm, work done against Gravitational force between them to take the particle far away from them.",
      "correct_answer": "A) 13.34x10^-10J",
      "options": [
          "A) 13.34x10^-10J",
          "B) 3.33x10^-10J",
          "C) 6.67x10^-10J",
          "D) 6.67x10^-11J"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A coolie carrying some load on his head & walking along a horizontal platform does...",
      "correct_answer": "B) Zero work",
      "options": [
          "A) +ve work",
          "B) Zero work",
          "C) -ve work",
          "D) None of These"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "When a body is lifted upward work done by gravity is...",
      "correct_answer": "A) +ve",
      "options": [
          "A) +ve",
          "B) -ve",
          "C) Zero",
          "D) None of These"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "When force and displacement are perpendicular, then work is...",
      "correct_answer": "C) Zero",
      "options": [
          "A) Positive",
          "B) Negative",
          "C) Zero",
          "D) All of These"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A block of mass 2kg is pushed 2m along a frictionless horizontal table by a constant force of 15N. Then work done by the normal force exerted by the table...",
      "correct_answer": "C) 120J",
      "options": [
          "A) 30J",
          "B) 60J",
          "C) 120J",
          "D) 0J"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A body is moved along a straight line by a machine delivering constant power. The velocity gained by the body in time 't' is proportional to...",
      "correct_answer": "B) 3/t^2",
      "options": [
          "A) 3/t^4",
          "B) 3/t^2",
          "C) 1/t^4",
          "D) 1/t^2"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The examples of potential energy are...",
      "correct_answer": "D) All of These",
      "options": [
          "A) Stretched bow",
          "B) Water stored in a dam",
          "C) Electron in an Electric field",
          "D) All of These"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A body of mass 10kg, initially at rest. If two forces 4N and 3N perpendicular to each other act upon it, then what is the K.E of the body after 10sec...",
      "correct_answer": "C) 300J",
      "options": [
          "A) 100J",
          "B) 125J",
          "C) 300J",
          "D) 50J"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A ball is thrown vertically up with velocity 20m/s. At what height will its K.E be half its original value...",
      "correct_answer": "D) h/2",
      "options": [
          "A) 2h",
          "B) h/3",
          "C) 2h/3",
          "D) h/2"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The work done against gravitational force...",
      "correct_answer": "C) Fd",
      "options": [
          "A) mgh",
          "B) -mgh",
          "C) Fd",
          "D) 0"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "When a body moves from infinity, the G.P.E is...",
      "correct_answer": "C) -mgh",
      "options": [
          "A) 0",
          "B) +mgh",
          "C) -mgh",
          "D) mgh/2"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The ratio of K.E of two objects of masses 2m and m is 8:1. The ratio of their linear momenta is...",
      "correct_answer": "D) 8:1",
      "options": [
          "A) 1:1",
          "B) 2:1",
          "C) 4:1",
          "D) 8:1"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The main source of energy in Pakistan...",
      "correct_answer": "B) Hydroelectricity",
      "options": [
          "A) Gasoline",
          "B) Hydroelectricity",
          "C) Fossil-fuel",
          "D) Wind"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A truck of mass 30,000kg moves up an inclined plane of slope of sin=1/100 at a speed of 30km/h. The power of the truck is (g=10m/s^2)...",
      "correct_answer": "A) 25KW",
      "options": [
          "A) 25KW",
          "B) 10KW",
          "C) 5KW",
          "D) 2.5KW"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following is not Correct?",
      "correct_answer": "(d) Work done by gravitational force depends upon path",
      "options": [
          "(a) Work done by variable force calculated by F.r",
          "(b) Work done during variable force, force change only in magnitude",
          "(c) Work done by variable force equal to area under curve",
          "(d) Work done by gravitational force depends upon path"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A 300J of work is done in sliding a 2kg block up an inclined plane of height 10m, work against friction is...",
      "correct_answer": "(c) 100J",
      "options": [
          "(a) 1000J",
          "(b) 200J",
          "(c) 100J",
          "(d) Zero"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "K.E of a body, if its mass & velocity are doubled…",
      "correct_answer": "(c) 8K",
      "options": [
          "(a) 2K",
          "(b) 4K",
          "(c) 8K",
          "(d) 16K"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A force of 400N is required to overcome road friction and air resistance in propelling an automobile at 80m/s. what power (kW) must the engine develop?",
      "correct_answer": "(b) 3.2kW",
      "options": [
          "(a) 3.2x10^3W",
          "(b) 3.2kW",
          "(c) 320kW",
          "(d) 32kW"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A metal ball of mass 2kg moving with speed of 10m/s undergoes a head-on collision with stationary ball of mass 3kg. If after collision, both the balls move together, then the loss in K.E due to collision is...",
      "correct_answer": "(c) 100J",
      "options": [
          "(a) 40J",
          "(b) 60J",
          "(c) 100J",
          "(d) 140J"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Energy release during supernova.",
      "correct_answer": "(b) 1050J",
      "options": [
          "(a) 1044J",
          "(b) 1050J",
          "(c) 1052J",
          "(d) 1032J"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The work done by a variable force moving a particle between two points is equal to...",
      "correct_answer": "(c) Area under curve",
      "options": [
          "(a) Displacement",
          "(b) K.E",
          "(c) Area under curve",
          "(d) F&d"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Work done by the earth's gravitational field is...",
      "correct_answer": "(c) Independent of position",
      "options": [
          "(a) Depends upon path",
          "(b) Depends upon position",
          "(c) Independent of position",
          "(d) All of These"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A particle of mass M starting from rest undergoes uniform acceleration. If the speed acquired in time T is v, the power delivered to the particle is...",
      "correct_answer": "(b) Mv^2/2T^2",
      "options": [
          "(a) Mv^2/T",
          "(b) Mv^2/2T^2",
          "(c) Mv^2/T^2",
          "(d) Mv^2/2T"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Fossil fuels are...",
      "correct_answer": "(b) Crude oil, gas, coal, peat, and lignite",
      "options": [
          "(a) Coal and petrol",
          "(b) Crude oil, gas, coal, peat, and lignite",
          "(c) Only petrol",
          "(d) Only coal"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "In rubbing our hands, we convert:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) Mechanical into heat energy",
      "options": [
          "(a) Mechanical into heat energy",
          "(b) Heat into mechanical energy",
          "(c) Heat into chemical energy",
          "(d) Chemical into heat energy"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "In the present age, the main source of energy is:",
      "correct_answer": "(b) Fossil fuel",
      "options": [
          "(a) Gasoline",
          "(b) Fossil fuel",
          "(c) Petrol",
          "(d) Coal"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The work-energy equation is:",
      "correct_answer": "(b) K.E = mgh - fh",
      "options": [
          "(a) K.E = mgh + fh",
          "(b) K.E = mgh - fh",
          "(c) P.E = K.E + fh",
          "(d) K.E = fd"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The absolute P.E of a body of mass (m) lying at the surface of the earth is given by:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) -mgh",
      "options": [
          "(a) -mgh",
          "(b) +mgh",
          "(c) -mgh/2",
          "(d) mgh"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following is not a unit of electrical power:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) KWH",
      "options": [
          "(a) KW",
          "(b) Watt",
          "(c) J/S",
          "(d) KWH"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following is an example of +Ve work.",
      "correct_answer": "(a) Work by stretching spring",
      "options": [
          "(a) Work by stretching spring",
          "(b) Work by lifting force",
          "(c) Work by gravitational force",
          "(d) All of These"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A force of 5N acts on a 15kg body initially at rest. The work done by the force during the first second of motion of the body is:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) 5 J",
      "options": [
          "(a) 5 J",
          "(b) 5/6 J",
          "(c) 0 J",
          "(d) 0.5 J"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The work done against gravity in taking a 10kg mass to a 1m height in 1 second will be:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) 19.6 J",
      "options": [
          "(a) 49 J",
          "(b) 98 J",
          "(c) 196 J",
          "(d) 19.6 J"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A 50kg mass of a man with a 20kg load on his head climbs up 20 steps of 0.5m height each. The work done in climbing is:",
      "correct_answer": "(b) 350 J",
      "options": [
          "(a) 5 J",
          "(b) 350 J",
          "(c) 100 J",
          "(d) 3430 J"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "If the K.E of a particle is doubled, then its momentum will be:",
      "correct_answer": "(c) Be doubled",
      "options": [
          "(a) Remains unchanged",
          "(b) Be quadrupled",
          "(c) Be doubled",
          "(d) Increase"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "According to the work-energy relation, the work done by the net force acting on a particle is equal to the change in:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) K.E",
      "options": [
          "(a) K.E",
          "(b) P.E",
          "(c) Linear momentum",
          "(d) Acceleration"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "In which case does the potential energy decrease:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) On compressing a spring",
      "options": [
          "(a) On compressing a spring",
          "(b) On stretching a spring",
          "(c) On mass of a body lifted against G.F",
          "(d) On rising of an air bubble in work"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "If the velocity of a body is twice that of its previous velocity, then its K.E will be:",
      "correct_answer": "(c) 4 times",
      "options": [
          "(a) 2 times",
          "(b) 1/2 times",
          "(c) 4 times",
          "(d) 1 times"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The power of a pump is 2KW. If (x) the amount of water it can raise in one minute to a height of 50m:",
      "correct_answer": "(b) 1000 liter",
      "options": [
          "(a) 200 liter",
          "(b) 1000 liter",
          "(c) 100 liter",
          "(d) 1200 liter"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "An engine develops 10kW of power. How much time will it take to lift a mass of 200kg to a height of 40m:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) 4 sec",
      "options": [
          "(a) 4 sec",
          "(b) 5 sec",
          "(c) 8 sec",
          "(d) 10 sec"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A lighter body and a heavier body have equal K.E, which has greater momentum:",
      "correct_answer": "(b) Heavier body",
      "options": [
          "(a) Lighter body",
          "(b) Heavier body",
          "(c) Both",
          "(d) None of These"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "If force and displacement of a particle in the direction of force are doubled, the work would be:",
      "correct_answer": "(b) 4 times",
      "options": [
          "(a) Double",
          "(b) 4 times",
          "(c) Half",
          "(d) ¼ times"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "1 kilowatt-hour = ____________.",
      "correct_answer": "(b) 3.6x10^6 J",
      "options": [
          "(a) 3.6x10^5 J",
          "(b) 3.6x10^6 J",
          "(c) 36x10^6 J",
          "(d) 3.6x10^7 J"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A body of mass 100 kg is lifted to a height of 100 cm from the Earth's surface, and then the work done by the lifting force is __________.",
      "correct_answer": "(b) 9800 J",
      "options": [
          "(a) 98 J",
          "(b) 9800 J",
          "(c) 980 J",
          "(d) 9.8 J"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following relations is correct?",
      "correct_answer": "(d) Both A & B",
      "options": [
          "(a) K.E = ½ m x",
          "(b) K.E = Fd",
          "(c) P = x",
          "(d) Both A & B"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Energy released during supernova explosions:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) MeV",
      "options": [
          "(a) J",
          "(b) J",
          "(c) eV",
          "(d) MeV"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The product of the magnitude of force and the components of displacement in the direction of force:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) Work",
      "options": [
          "(a) Work",
          "(b) Power",
          "(c) Energy",
          "(d) Force"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "When the force acts at right angles to the displacement, the work is:",
      "correct_answer": "(b) Zero work",
      "options": [
          "(a) Positive work",
          "(b) Zero work",
          "(c) Negative work",
          "(d) None of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following is a correct statement?",
      "correct_answer": "(d) Both A and C",
      "options": [
          "(a) When the body moves in the direction of gravitational force, the work is done by the force of gravity, positive",
          "(b) When the body moves in the direction of gravitational force, work done is negative",
          "(c) If the person walks along a level surface carrying a box, no work is done",
          "(d) Both A and C"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "If the work done by that force on a particle that moves between two points depends on the path between these points is:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) Non-conservative field",
      "options": [
          "(a) Gravitational field",
          "(b) Electric field",
          "(c) Conservative field",
          "(d) Non-conservative field"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following is an incorrect statement?",
      "correct_answer": "(b) Work by centripetal force zero",
      "options": [
          "(a) Work by frictional forces negative",
          "(b) Work by centripetal force zero",
          "(c) Frictional forces are conservative force",
          "(d) Work by lifting forces is positive"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following examples has Gravitational P.E.?",
      "correct_answer": "(d) All of these",
      "options": [
          "(a) Water stored in a dam has P.E",
          "(b) A stretched bow has P.E",
          "(c) An electron or proton in an electric field has P.E",
          "(d) All of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "1 watt is equal to_________:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) 746 erg",
      "options": [
          "(a) erg",
          "(b) erg/s",
          "(c) erg",
          "(d) 746 erg"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A constant force of 100 N acts for 5 seconds on a body of mass 10 kg initially at rest. Find the work done:",
      "correct_answer": "(c) 12500 J",
      "options": [
          "(a) 125 J",
          "(b) 1250 J",
          "(c) 12500 J",
          "(d) 125000 J"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A car of mass 2000 kg is lifted up through a distance of 30 m by crane in one minute, a second crane does the same job in 2 minutes, what power is supplied by the second crane:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) W",
      "options": [
          "(a) W",
          "(b) W",
          "(c) W",
          "(d) W"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "What change produces in K.E of a body if mass and velocity are doubled:",
      "correct_answer": "(c) 8 times",
      "options": [
          "(a) 4 times",
          "(b) 2 times",
          "(c) 8 times",
          "(d) Remains the same"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The work displacing the body by variable forces from one point to another is exactly equal to:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) Area under the curve",
      "options": [
          "(a) Area under the curve",
          "(b) Displacement",
          "(c) Force",
          "(d) Path"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The energy possessed by a body by virtue of its motion:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) K.E",
      "options": [
          "(a) K.E",
          "(b) P.E",
          "(c) G.P.E",
          "(d) Abs G.P.E"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "When a body of mass (m) is lifted upward by external forces equal in magnitude to that of the force of gravity, then K.E is:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) 0",
      "options": [
          "(a) mv^2",
          "(b) mgh",
          "(c) –",
          "(d) 0"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The P.E of a body in the Earth's gravitational field at height 'h' is:",
      "correct_answer": "(b) –mgh",
      "options": [
          "(a) mgh",
          "(b) –mgh",
          "(c) 0",
          "(d) None of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The P.E of the body at a certain height with respect to that at infinity is:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) mgh + Fs",
      "options": [
          "(a) mgh",
          "(b) –mgh",
          "(c) 0",
          "(d) mgh + Fs"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
      "correct_answer": "(b) As a particle moves in from infinity, the work is negative",
      "options": [
          "(a) The P.E decreases as the separation distance decreases from infinity",
          "(b) As a particle moves in from infinity, the work is negative",
          "(c) P.E is negative at an infinite distance",
          "(d) All of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The Work-Energy equation is:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) None of these",
      "options": [
          "(a) K.E = mgh + fh",
          "(b) K.E = mgh – fh",
          "(c) P.E = K.E + fh",
          "(d) None of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "In the present age, the main source of energy is:",
      "correct_answer": "(c) Coal",
      "options": [
          "(a) Hydroelectricity",
          "(b) Nuclear energy",
          "(c) Coal",
          "(d) Gasoline"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The destruction of Japan due to the atomic bomb is an example of:",
      "correct_answer": "(c) Uncontrolled Nuclear Fission",
      "options": [
          "(a) Nuclear Fusion reaction",
          "(b) Controlled Nuclear Fission",
          "(c) Uncontrolled Nuclear Fission",
          "(d) Controlled Nuclear Fusion"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "In Pakistan, the main source of energy is:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) Fossil Fuel",
      "options": [
          "(a) Hydro Electricity",
          "(b) Solar Energy",
          "(c) Thermal Energy",
          "(d) Fossil Fuel"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "For tidal energy, the origin of tides is due to:",
      "correct_answer": "(b) Gravitational forces between Earth and Moon",
      "options": [
          "(a) Gravitational forces between Moon and Sun",
          "(b) Gravitational forces between Earth and Moon",
          "(c) Gravitational forces between Earth and Sun",
          "(d) Gravitational force between Earth and other planets"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A person pushed a toy car initially at rest with a force of 10 N through a distance of 1 m. The work done is:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) 10 J",
      "options": [
          "(a) 10 J",
          "(b) 5 J",
          "(c) 2 J",
          "(d) 1 J"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Heat energy conducts out from the interior of the surface of the Earth at a rate of:",
      "correct_answer": "(c) 1.5 cal/cm²",
      "options": [
          "(a) 1.5 J",
          "(b) 1.5 MeV",
          "(c) 1.5 cal/cm²",
          "(d) 1.5 eV"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following statements is correct?",
      "correct_answer": "(d) Both A and C",
      "options": [
          "(a) Solar energy is an ideal source to get rid of pollution.",
          "(b) Solar energy is applicable for space heating and space cooling.",
          "(c) The main source of energy in Pakistan is coal.",
          "(d) Both A and C"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "When an object thrown upward at a height (h) loses 1/4th of its original kinetic energy, how high is the object in terms of h?",
      "correct_answer": "(a) 4h",
      "options": [
          "(a) 4h",
          "(b) 3h",
          "(c)",
          "(d)"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "If the mass of a body is 10 kg and it is annihilated, then its energy is:",
      "correct_answer": "(c) MeV",
      "options": [
          "(a) 10 J",
          "(b) 90 J",
          "(c) MeV",
          "(d) eV"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "When no force of friction is involved during the free fall motion of a body, then the loss of potential energy is equal to:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) K.E",
      "options": [
          "(a) K.E",
          "(b) K.E + Fh",
          "(c) K.E - Fh",
          "(d) P.E - Fh"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A 20 kg mass is thrown upward and it reaches its greatest height of 10 m. Then the potential energy at the greatest height is:",
      "correct_answer": "(b) 196 J",
      "options": [
          "(a) 90.6 J",
          "(b) 196 J",
          "(c) 19.6 J",
          "(d) 1960 J"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The absolute gravitational potential energy at the surface of the Earth:",
      "correct_answer": "(c) 0",
      "options": [
          "(a)",
          "(b)",
          "(c) 0",
          "(d)"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Energy released during a Quasar explosion:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) all of these",
      "options": [
          "(a) J",
          "(b) J",
          "(c) erg",
          "(d) all of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A German physicist Hermann von Helmholtz enunciated the general law regarding energy in:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) 1847",
      "options": [
          "(a) 1847",
          "(b) 1890",
          "(c) 1905",
          "(d) 1932"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "When the force and displacement are along the same direction, then work is:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) Positive work",
      "options": [
          "(a) Positive work",
          "(b) Zero work",
          "(c) Negative work",
          "(d) None of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The concept of work provides a link between:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) Force & displacement",
      "options": [
          "(a) Force & displacement",
          "(b) Force & energy",
          "(c) Force & velocity",
          "(d) Power & energy"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "If the work done by the force on a particle that moves between two points depends on the path between these points, it is a:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) Non-conservative field",
      "options": [
          "(a) Gravitational field",
          "(b) Electric field",
          "(c) Conservative field",
          "(d) Non-conservative field"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following is a correct statement?",
      "correct_answer": "(a) Work by gravitational forces is negative",
      "options": [
          "(a) Work by gravitational forces is negative",
          "(b) Work by centripetal force is negative",
          "(c) Frictional forces are conservative forces",
          "(d) Work by lifting forces is positive"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following is not a unit of work:",
      "correct_answer": "(c) kWh",
      "options": [
          "(a) Joule",
          "(b) BTU",
          "(c) kWh",
          "(d) kW"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The work is done when:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) Displacement in the direction of force",
      "options": [
          "(a) Displacement in the direction of force",
          "(b) Displacement perpendicular to the direction of force",
          "(c) Displacement opposite to the direction of force",
          "(d) None of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A constant force of 10 N acts for 2 sec on a body of mass 5 kg initially at rest. The work done is:",
      "correct_answer": "(b) 20 J",
      "options": [
          "(a) 10 J",
          "(b) 20 J",
          "(c) 40 J",
          "(d) 100 J"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following is an example of positive work?",
      "correct_answer": "(a) Work done by stretching force",
      "options": [
          "(a) Work done by stretching force",
          "(b) Work done by lifting force",
          "(c) Work done by gravitational force",
          "(d) All of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Work can be positive or negative depending on the value of:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) b and c",
      "options": [
          "(a) Magnitude of force and displacement",
          "(b) Direction of displacement & force",
          "(c) Angle between force & displacement",
          "(d) b and c"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Work done by the gravitational force on a body being lifted is:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) Positive",
      "options": [
          "(a) Positive",
          "(b) Negative",
          "(c) Zero",
          "(d) None of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "If a person walks along a level surface while carrying a box, the work is:",
      "correct_answer": "(c) Negative work",
      "options": [
          "(a) Positive work",
          "(b) Zero work",
          "(c) Negative work",
          "(d) All of these"
      ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "When a body slides along a surface, the work done by the normal force acting on the body is:",
    "correct_answer": "D) Fd",
    "options": [
      "A) Fd",
      "B) Fd",
      "C) 0",
      "D) Fd"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "A body of mass 20 kg moving along a circular path with a covered displacement of 20 m with the application of 10 N force, calculate work done?",
    "correct_answer": "B) 200 Joule",
    "options": [
      "A) 20 Joule",
      "B) 200 Joule",
      "C) 400 Joule",
      "D) 0 Joule"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "One electron volt is equal to:",
    "correct_answer": "C) erg",
    "options": [
      "A) J",
      "B) J",
      "C) erg",
      "D) erg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "1 _______ Joule",
    "correct_answer": "A) 1055",
    "options": [
      "A) 1055",
      "B) 252",
      "C) 4180",
      "D) 4.8"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "The work done by gravitational force is:",
    "correct_answer": "C) 0",
    "options": [
      "A) ",
      "B) ",
      "C) 0",
      "D) Fd"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "Work done against gravitational force depends upon:",
    "correct_answer": "D) a and c",
    "options": [
      "A) Initial position of body",
      "B) Path covered by body",
      "C) Final position of body",
      "D) a and c"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "Which of the following is incorrect:",
    "correct_answer": "B) Work done in moving body along any close path is maximum",
    "options": [
      "A) Work done in moving body along any close path is zero",
      "B) Work done in moving body along any close path is maximum",
      "C) Work done in moving body against gravitational force is negative",
      "D) Work done in gravitational field is independent of the path"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "Which of the following is non-conservative force:",
    "correct_answer": "C) Frictional force",
    "options": [
      "A) Gravitational force",
      "B) Restoring force",
      "C) Frictional force",
      "D) Electrical force"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "One megawatt _______ kg.",
    "correct_answer": "D) kg",
    "options": [
      "A) kg",
      "B) kg",
      "C) kg",
      "D) kg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "A person pushed a toy car initially at rest with a force of 10 N through a distance of 20 m. Work done is:",
    "correct_answer": "C) 200 J",
    "options": [
      "A) 10 J",
      "B) 20 J",
      "C) 200 J",
      "D) 150 J"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "The work done in one hour by an agency working at a constant rate of 1 kW (1000 Joules per second) is called:",
    "correct_answer": "A) 1 kWh",
    "options": [
      "A) 1 kWh",
      "B) 1 kJ",
      "C) 1 kW",
      "D) 1 BTU"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "Which of the following statements is correct:",
    "correct_answer": "D) All of these",
    "options": [
      "A) In work done by a variable force, the force changes only in direction",
      "B) In work done by a variable force, the force changes only in magnitude",
      "C) In work done by a variable force, the force changes in magnitude and direction",
      "D) All of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "When an object thrown upward at a height (h) has lost half of its original kinetic energy, how high is the object in terms of h?",
    "correct_answer": "A) 4h",
    "options": [
      "A) 4h",
      "B) 3h",
      "C) ",
      "D) "
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "Work done in displacing a body by a variable force is exactly equal to:",
    "correct_answer": "B) Area under curve",
    "options": [
      "A) Displacement",
      "B) Area under curve",
      "C) Volume",
      "D) None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "A horse pulls a cart horizontally with a force of 40 N at an angle above the horizontal and moves along at a speed of 6 m/s, completing its work in 10 seconds. What is the power output of the horse?",
    "correct_answer": "C) 260 W",
    "options": [
      "A) 120 W",
      "B) 240 W",
      "C) 260 W",
      "D) 290 W"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "A pump is needed to lift water through a height of 100 cm at a rate of 1000 g/s. What must be the minimum power of the pump?",
    "correct_answer": "A) 980 W",
    "options": [
      "A) 980 W",
      "B) 98 W",
      "C) 9.8 W",
      "D) None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "A 10 kg block initially at rest moves with a horizontal displacement of 10 m with a force of 20 N. Calculate the work done.",
    "correct_answer": "C) 200 Joule",
    "options": [
      "A) 0 Joule",
      "B) 300 Joule",
      "C) 200 Joule",
      "D) 150 Joule"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "The energy possessed by a body by virtue of its motion is:",
    "correct_answer": "C) Kinetic energy",
    "options": [
      "A) Gravitational potential energy",
      "B) Elastic potential energy",
      "C) Kinetic energy",
      "D) Absolute gravitational potential energy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "A neutron travels a distance of 10 m in a time interval of. Assuming its speed was constant, find its kinetic energy. Take as the mass of the neutron.",
    "correct_answer": "B) Joule",
    "options": [
      "A) ",
      "B) Joule",
      "C) ",
      "D) Joule"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "When an electric charge is moved against an electrostatic force, then electric potential energy:",
    "correct_answer": "B) Decrease",
    "options": [
      "A) Increase",
      "B) Decrease",
      "C) Remain the same",
      "D) Zero"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "When a body of mass m is lifted to a height “h” against the gravitational force, the work done on it is:",
    "correct_answer": "D) 2mgh",
    "options": [
      "A) mgh",
      "B) mgh",
      "C) 0",
      "D) 2mgh"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "Which of the following is an example of kinetic energy?",
    "correct_answer": "D) All of these",
    "options": [
      "A) Falling water",
      "B) Winds",
      "C) A moving ball that can break a glass window",
      "D) All of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "Water stored in a dam has _______ energy.",
    "correct_answer": "B) Potential Energy",
    "options": [
      "A) Kinetic Energy",
      "B) Potential Energy",
      "C) Absolute Potential Energy",
      "D) Electric Potential Energy"
    ]
  },
  {
    "category": "Physics",
    "type": "multiple",
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "question": "A stretched bow has _______ energy.",
    "correct_answer": "C) Elastic Potential Energy",
    "options": [
      "A) Gravitational Potential Energy",
      "B) Electrostatic Potential Energy",
      "C) Elastic Potential Energy",
      "D) Absolute Potential Energy"
    ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following statement is correct:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) All of these",
      "options": [
          "(a) At the maximum height K.E of the body is maximum",
          "(b) At the maximum height K.E of the body is zero",
          "(c) At the maximum height GPE of the body is zero",
          "(d) All of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "During upward motion, when the applied force on the body by external agency is equal in magnitude to that of force of gravity under this condition kinetic energy of body:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) 0",
      "options": [
          "(a) 0",
          "(b) ",
          "(c) ",
          "(d) None of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The potential energy of body in the earth’s gravitational field at a height h is:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) mgh",
      "options": [
          "(a) mgh",
          "(b) mgh",
          "(c) Fd",
          "(d) "
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The potential energy of the body at height “h” from centre of earth where gravitational field is zero is:",
      "correct_answer": "(c) Absolute gravitational potential energy",
      "options": [
          "(a) Gravitational potential energy",
          "(b) Kinetic energy",
          "(c) Absolute gravitational potential energy",
          "(d) Electric potential energy"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The gravitational potential energy at infinite distance:",
      "correct_answer": "(c) 0",
      "options": [
          "(a) mgh",
          "(b) mgh",
          "(c) 0",
          "(d) None of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "As the particle moves in from infinity the gravitational potential is:",
      "correct_answer": "(b) 0",
      "options": [
          "(a) mgh",
          "(b) 0",
          "(c) mgh",
          "(d) mgh"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The absolute gravitational potential of a body of mass “m” lying at surface of earth is given by:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) ",
      "options": [
          "(a) ",
          "(b) ",
          "(c) ",
          "(d) "
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following is correct statement:",
      "correct_answer": "(c) As body moves from infinity work is zero",
      "options": [
          "(a) As body moves from infinity work is positive",
          "(b) As body moves from infinity work is negative",
          "(c) As body moves from infinity work is zero",
          "(d) At infinity gravitational potential is maximum"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following is work energy relation:",
      "correct_answer": "(b) Gain in K.E = Loss of P.E",
      "options": [
          "(a) Gain in K.E = Fd",
          "(b) Gain in K.E = Loss of P.E",
          "(c) Loss of P.E = K.E",
          "(d) w"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "During the fall of the body assuming that there is no friction, P.E is equal to:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) ",
      "options": [
          "(a) ",
          "(b) ",
          "(c) ",
          "(d) None of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "When we switch on our electric bulbs, we supply electrical energy to their filaments it is converted into:",
      "correct_answer": "(b) Light & heat energy",
      "options": [
          "(a) Light & mechanical energy",
          "(b) Light & heat energy",
          "(c) Chemical & heat energy",
          "(d) Electrical energy"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Fossil fuels are:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) All of these",
      "options": [
          "(a) coal",
          "(b) petrol",
          "(c) peat, lignite",
          "(d) All of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of following is correct relation:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) A – C",
      "options": [
          "(a) P = ",
          "(b) W = ",
          "(c) K.E = 1/2 m ",
          "(d) A – C"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Proton, electron & neutron have same momentum, which of them have highest K.E?",
      "correct_answer": "(a) Electron",
      "options": [
          "(a) Electron",
          "(b) Proton",
          "(c) Neutron",
          "(d) Proton & Neutron"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Work done on the body equal to the:",
      "correct_answer": "(c) Change in K.E & P.E",
      "options": [
          "(a) Change in K.E",
          "(b) Change in its P.E",
          "(c) Change in K.E & P.E",
          "(d) None of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The source of geothermal energy is:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) Radioactive decay of earth",
      "options": [
          "(a) Radioactive decay of earth",
          "(b) Interior compression of earth",
          "(c) Atmosphere temperature of earth",
          "(d) Atmosphere pressure of earth"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "If the velocity of body is double, then:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) Momentum increase 2 times & kinetic energy 4 times",
      "options": [
          "(a) Kinetic energy increase 2 times & Momentum increase 4 times",
          "(b) Momentum & kinetic energy remain same",
          "(c) Momentum increase 2 times & kinetic energy constant",
          "(d) Momentum increase 2 times & kinetic energy 4 times"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "In present age the main source of energy is:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) Nuclear energy",
      "options": [
          "(a) Solar energy",
          "(b) Gasoline",
          "(c) Hydroelectricity",
          "(d) Nuclear energy"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "In rubbing our hands we convert:",
      "correct_answer": "(c) Mechanical into heat energy",
      "options": [
          "(a) Mechanical energy into electrical energy",
          "(b) Mechanical energy into chemical energy",
          "(c) Mechanical into heat energy",
          "(d) Heat energy into mechanical energy"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "Which of the following is correct statement:",
      "correct_answer": "(d) All of these",
      "options": [
          "(a) Solar energy providing clean fuels",
          "(b) Solar energy is ideal source of energy but it produce lot of pollution",
          "(c) Nuclear energy is produce due to fusion process of heavy nucleus",
          "(d) All of these"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "The main source of energy in Pakistan:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) Hydroelectricity",
      "options": [
          "(a) Hydroelectricity",
          "(b) Geothermal energy",
          "(c) Nuclear energy",
          "(d) Fossil fuel"
      ]
  },
  {
      "category": "Physics",
      "type": "multiple",
      "difficulty": "medium",
      "question": "A pump is needed to lift water of 100 gm through height of 0.5 m. Calculate change in potential energy:",
      "correct_answer": "(a) 490 joule",
      "options": [
          "(a) 490 joule",
          "(b) 49 joule",
          "(c) 4.9 joule",
          "(d) 0.490 joule"
      ]
  }
]
}